sundayherald.com 2015-03-16

# Privacy Policy | Herald Scotland

This site is owned and operated by the Herald & Times Group. We are committed to protecting your right to personal privacy. That is why we have drafted this notice to explain the type of information we collect on this web site (the "Site") and how we use this information. In this Privacy Policy, when we say "Site" we mean the digital information network regardless of how you access it, including but not limited to the World Wide Web, mobile phone, mobile apps, email alerts and RSS feeds. This Policy also explains the choices that you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

By using this web site you are deemed as agreeing to use of these details as described in this Policy. We appreciate that this Policy may seem long, however, we have created a thorough privacy statement to fully explain our information handling practices. Should you have any questions however, please feel free to direct these to [support@heraldandtimes.co.uk](mailto:support@heraldandtimes.co.uk)

###  Information we collect - personally identifiable information

We request identifying information from you for specific purposes. Typically, identifying information is collected:

  * For registration to certain areas of the Site;
  * To allow us to respond to your enquiries for further information;
  * To distribute requested materials;
  * When you are submitting user generated content such as comments or photographs
  * The type of personal information collected on the Site could include your name, address, email address, telephone number, user name and password.

###  Information we collect - non-personally identifiable information

We collect non-personally identifiable data, known as 'click-stream data', across the portfolio of web sites owned by the Herald and Times Group. This click stream data is anonymous, and includes information such as IP address, which pages have been visited and what actions have been taken.

We use cookies to collect this type of information. Cookies are files or pieces of information that may be stored on your computer's hard drive when you visit a site. The use of cookies is an industry standard and you will find them at most sites. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. However, you can set your browser to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent so that you can flush them from your browser if you object to their presence. Find out more about how we use cookies.

Additionally, we use demographics and interest reports based display advertising data provided by our advertising partners. Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

###  The way we use information

We may occasionally request your postcode details in order to ensure that we only deliver information relevant to you and only where we have obtained your prior express permission to do so. We will NOT use your postcode information to generate a full postal address (where completion of full address fields are not requested), nor will we mail out literature related to our websites unless you specifically request us to do so.

When you register with the Site, you can elect to receive information and updates on our products and services by email and SMS. Will not use these addresses for any other purpose unless you give us your express permission to do so.

We use return email addresses to answer any emails that we receive, and we may use return email addresses to send you other information that you request. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose.

We use the non-personally identifiable information we collect, including data collected by cookies, to track user trends - for example how users search for content - to provide you with a tailored experience and to improve the quality of our services. We may also use cookies to help speed up your future activities or to improve your user experience by remembering the information that you have already provided to us. If you have submitted personally identifiable information to one of our websites then we may combine this information with the non-personally identifiable information that we collect in order to further enhance the service that we provide.

You will have the opportunity to forward pages or information on the Site to friends. The information you provide to facilitate this email communication is used on a one-time basis and is not collected or retained by us.

We make every practical effort to avoid excessive or irrelevant collection of data. If you believe the Site has collected excessive information, we encourage you to contact us at support@heraldandtimes.co.uk

###  Unsubscribe / Delete

You have the right to access personal data which you have submitted through the Site. We give you the following options for managing or removing your information from our database:

Manage Your Profile: Within the "my account" section you have the option to manage your personal profile. The management system allows you to update your information on our database. We also allow you to subscribe or unsubscribe to any of the email updates you've requested from the site.

Send us mail:  Herald & Times Group, 200 Renfield Street, Glasgow, G2 3QB, Scotland. Be sure to include your name and clear instructions on what you would like us to do.

Send us an email: at support@heraldandtimes.co.uk. Be sure to include your name and clear instructions on what you would like us to do.

###  Our Privacy Practices with Third Parties

It is our policy to only disclose information to third parties under the following circumstances:

  * As required by law
  * When explicitly requested by a user
  * When required to deliver products or services requested by a user and with their express permission

We share aggregate, non-personally identifiable information about our users with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and other third parties. Subject to the above three circumstances, we do not provide any identifiable personal information to any third party for any purpose whatsoever. For example, we may tell a business partner the number of men and the number of women that entered a competition, but we do not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals. Access by our employees and agents to your personally identifiable information are only on a need to know basis on the understanding that this is confidential business information.

Our intention is never to use or share personally identifiable information provided to us in ways that are different than the ways described above without also providing you with an opportunity to "unsubscribe" or prohibit such unrelated uses.

###  Links to Other Sites

Because we want your experience of the Site to be as informative and useful as possible, we provide a number of links to third party sites. Always be aware of where you end up. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, or otherwise collect data or solicit personal information. We assume no responsibility for the information practices of sites that you are able to access through ours, and we encourage you to review each site's privacy policy before disclosing any personally identifiable information.

###  Our Commitment to Data Security

We take reasonable precautions to keep your personal information secure. We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect. We cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online, and you do so at your own risk. Note that some parts of our service, such as commenting, requires the storage of some of your information outside the European Union.

###  **Changes in Our Policy**

**We reserve the right to change or remove this Privacy Policy at our discretion. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy we will post those changes here. We encourage you to visit this area frequently so as to stay informed. If there is any material change in the type of personally identifiable information we collect we will obtain your permission before we attempt to collect the additional personal information. We will not make any changes that allow us to give personal information to a third party without obtaining permission from you first.**

###  **Your Consent to this Privacy Policy**

**By using the Site, you signify your agreement to be bound by this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with any term in this Policy, please do not use the Site or submit any personally identifiable information.**

###  **How to Contact Us**

**Should you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or the collection of information, please e-mail us at support@heraldandtimes.co.uk**
